Guide to the Sports Information Office records, 1932-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Sports Information Office records 1932-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Sports Information Office.
19.5 linear feet Extent: approx. 5000 items
The Sports Information Office provides information about Duke athletics to the media. They also facilitate press interviews with Duke athletes and coaches. The collection contains press releases, photographs, audio reels, and other material pertaining to sports at Duke University. The date ranges from 1932-ongoing.
UA.13.02.0001
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Sports Information Office records were received by the University Archives as a transfer over time.
Historical Note
The Sports Information Office provides information about Duke athletics to the media. They also facilitate press interviews with Duke athletes and coaches. For many years, the Sports Information Office has maintained records, photographs and other material about Duke athletic teams.
Collection Overview
This collection includes press releases, photographs, clippings, scrapbooks, plaques, audio reels and other material pertaining to sports at Duke University. Topics range from individual sports (badminton, boxing, high school basketball) and the coaching school to freshmen sports. For ease of patron use, individual collections have been created for the bulk of sport-specific information. For example, there is a separate finding aid for both men and women's basketball, football, and baseball. Please see the list of Related Collections below for a comprehensive list. The collection ranges in date from 1932-ongoing.
Subject Headings
Duke University. Sports Information Office; Duke University -- Sports
Related Material
Baseball records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Basketball records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Cross Country/Track and Field records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Fencing records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Field Hockey records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Football records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Golf records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Gymnastics records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Lacrosse records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Rowing records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Soccer records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Swimming and Diving Team records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Tennis records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Women's Basketball records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Wrestling records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Volleyball records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- General Files, 1932-1991, 6 Boxes
  This series includes general files created by the Sports Information Office. It includes largely press releases but also clippings and files on high school basketball.
  - Badminton Championships Program, Cameron Indoor Stadium, April 1942 (Box 1)
  - Badminton National championships, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Boxing, 1932-1936 (Box 1)
  - Boxing, 1937-1940 (Box 1)
  - Charlotte Feature on Simons, Muse, and Chapman, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Coaching School, 1932-1935 (Box 1)
  - Coaching School, 1936-1940 (Box 1)
  - Composite spring Sports Schedules and Releases, 1956-1973 (17 folders) (Box 1)
  - Director: Correspondence, circa 1942-1943 (Box 1)
  - Football: General Stories, early 1940s (Box 1)
  - Freshmen Sports, 1933-1935 (Box 2)
  - Freshmen Sports, 1936-1939 (Box 2)
  - Freshmen Sports, 1948-1951 (Box 2)
  - Faculty Softball, 1933, 1949, undated (Box 2)
  - Intramurals, 1932-1947 (Box 2)
  - Register and Press Releases, 1933-1935 (Box 2)
  - Register and Press Releases, 1936-1939 (Box 2)
  - Register and Press Releases, 1939-1943 (Box 3)
  - Register and Press Releases, 1946-1949 (Box 3)
  - Spring Sports/Press Releases, 1950 (Box 3)
  - Spring Sports/Press Releases, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Spring Sports/Press Releases, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Press Releases, 1973 May-Dec. (Box 3)
  - Press Releases, 1974 Jan.-Dec. (Box 3)
  - Press Releases, 1975 Jan.-Dec. (Box 3)
  - Press Releases, 1976 Jan.-Dec. (Box 3)
  - Press Releases, 1977 Jan.-Dec. (Box 3)
  - Press Releases, 1978 Jan.-June (Box 3)
  - Press Releases, 1978 July-Dec. (Box 4)
  - Press Releases, 1979 Jan.-June (Box 4)
  - Press Releases, 1979 July-Dec. (Box 4)
  - Press Releases, 1980 Jan.-June (Box 4)
  - Press Releases, 1980 July-Dec. (Box 4)
  - Press Releases, 1981 Jan.-June (Box 4)
  - Press Releases, 1981 July-Dec. (Box 4)
  - Press Releases, 1982 Jan.-Dec. (Box 4)
  - Press Releases, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Press Releases, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Press Releases, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Press Releases, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Press Releases, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Press Releases, 1988 (Box 5)
  - Press Releases, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Press Releases, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Press Releases, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Southern High School Basketball Tournament, 1939-1946 (Box 5)
  - Southern High School, N.C. State High School Basketball Tournaments, circa 1940s (Box 5)
  - A Story of Glory, Ted Mann: Notes, correspondence, clippings (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - A Story of Glory, Final Manuscript (3 folders) (Box 6)
  - Summer School Sports, 1935; undated (Box 6)
  - Summaries and Miscellaneous, 1932-1934 (Box 6)
  - Track-Lacrosse-Crew, pre-1980 (Box 6)
  - Women's Athletics, 1973-1976 (Box 6)
  - Women's Schedules and Intercollegiates, pre-1980 (Box 6)
- Memorabilia and Oversize Material (including oversize photographs), 1937-1995, (5 boxes)
  This series contains oversize photograhs (some of which are mounted), oversize printed material, plaques, and scrapbooks.
  - Hall of Fame Bowl Plaque, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Color photograph from The Herald Sun of "The Shot," Basketball, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Final Four Minneapolis Pins (2), 1992 (Box 7)
  - Lacrosse, vol. 9, no. 2 (Jack Persons article), 1985 April (Box 7)
  - Signed broadside of Ben Bennett's ACC Record, circa 1983 (Box 7)
  - Facsimile of basketball team caricatures, undated (Box 7)
  - NCAA Basketball Media information, 1986 (Box 7)
  - World Top 20 Poll plaque, 1979 Dec. 17 (Box 7)
  - Ed Koffenberger, All-American, unmounted image, 1947 (Box 8)
  - Mounted images of the following All-American basketball players:
    - Ed Koffenberger (1946, 1947) (Box 8)
    - Dick Groat (1951, 1952) (Box 8)
    - Jeff Mullins (1964) (Box 8)
    - Jack Marin (1966) (Box 8)
    - Bob Verga (1966, 1967) (Box 8)
    - Mike Lewis (1968) (Box 8)
  - All-American certificates for baseball players:
    - Dick Groat (1952) (Box 8)
    - William Werber, Jr. (1952, 1954) (Box 8)
    - Albert Spangler (1954) (Box 8)
  - Oversize images of All-American football players and superlatives
    - Woody Lipscomb (1937) (Box 8)
    - Dan Hill, Jr. (1938) (Box 8)
    - Pat Preston (1943) (Box 8)
    - Bill Millner (1943, 1946) (Box 8)
    - Billy Cox (1950) (Box 8)
    - Jack Kistler (1951) (Box 8)
    - Red Smith (1951) (Box 8)
    - Dwight Bumgarner (1960) (Box 8)
    - Jean Berry (1962 (Box 8)
    - Jean Berry (1962) and Jay Wilkinson (1963) (Box 8)
    - Bob Matheson (1966) (Box 8)
  - AACBC District 3 Champs plaque, 1961 (Box 9 (Heavy box))
  - Art Gregory, Order of the Ahepa Athletic Hall of Fame plaque, 1981 (Box 9 (Heavy box))
  - Eddie Cameron resolution, 1972 (Box 9 (Heavy box))
  - Big Four Basketball Tournament Champs plaque, 1979-1980 (Box 9 (Heavy box))
  - Stanley Schneider and Leonard Merl plaque, early 1980s (Box 9 (Heavy box))
  - Rose Bowl Scrapbook, 1942 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook - Football, 1970; Basketball, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
- Media Guides and Publicity 1985-2000, (6 boxes)
  - Fencing (Box 12)
  - Men's Swimming (Box 12)
  - Women's Swimming (Box 12)
  - Men's Tennis (Box 12)
  - Rowing (Box 12)
  - Women's Lacrosse (Box 13)
  - Men's Soccer (Box 14)
  - Men's Golf (Box 15)
  - Track and Field (Men and Women) (Box 15)
  - Women's Soccer (Box 15)
  - Baseball (Box 15)
  - Misc./General (Box 16)
  - Women's Tennis (Box 16)
  - Wrestling (Box 16)
  - Field Hockey (Box 16)
  - Men's Lacrosse (Box 16)
  - Volleyball (Box 17)
  - Women's Golf (Box 17)
- Sound Recordings, 1982-1985, undated, (5 boxes)
  This series contains radio station broadcasts of Duke University football and basketball games recorded on 1/4 tape on 10-inch reels. Not all reels are labeled and not all distinguish between football and basketball.
  - Unlabeled, 1982 July 19 (Box 18)
  - Duke/Tennessee, 1982 Sept. 4 (Box 18)
  - Duke/Navy, 1982 Sept. 19 (2 reels) (Box 18)
  - Duke/Clemson, 1982 Oct. 16 (Box 18)
  - Duke/UNC, 1982 Nov. (2 reels) (Box 18)
  - Duke/ECU, 1982 Nov. 27 (Box 18)
  - Duke/Appalachian State, 1982 Nov. 30 (Box 18)
  - Duke/Colorado, 1982 Dec. 2 (Box 18)
  - Duke/Virginia, 1982 Dec. 8 (Box 18)
  - Duke/New Hampshire, 1982 Dec. 29 (Box 18)
  - Duke/Wagner, 1983 Jan. 5 (Box 18)
  - Duke/Lasalle, 1983 Jan. 8 (Box 18)
  - Duke/Louisville, 1983 Jan. 12 (Box 19)
  - Duke/Maryland, 1983 Jan. 15 (Box 19)
  - Duke/Wake Forest, 1983 Jan. 19 (Box 19)
  - Duke/UNC, 1983 Jan. 22 (Box 19)
  - Duke/NC State, 1983 Jan. 26 (Box 19)
  - Duke/William & Mary, 1983 Feb. 2 (Box 19)
  - Duke/Georgia Tech, 1983 Feb. 9 (Box 19)
  - Duke/Stetson, 1983 Feb. 16 (Box 19)
  - Duke/Wake Forest, 1983 Feb. 19 (Box 19)
  - Duke/Maryland, 1983 Feb. 21 (Box 19)
  - Duke/NC State, 1983 Feb. 23 (Box 19)
  - Unlabeled, 1983 Feb. 26 (Box 19)
  - Duke/Clemson, 1983 March 2 (Box 19)
  - Duke/UNC, 1983 March 5 (2 reels) (Box 20)
  - ACC Tournament: First half of NC State/Wake Forest, 1983 March 11 (Box 20)
  - ACC Tournament: Second half of NC State/Wake Forest; part of Duke/Virginia, 1983 March 11 (Box 20)
  - ACC Tournament: End of Duke/Virginia; all of Maryland/Georgia Tech, 1983 March 11 (Box 20)
  - Duke/Indiana, 1984 Sept. 8 (2 reels) (Box 20)
  - Duke/Army, 1984 Sept. 29 (Box 20)
  - Duke/Virginia, 1984 Oct. 6 (Box 20)
  - Duke/Virginia Tech, 1984 Oct. 13 (Box 20)
  - Duke/Clemson, 1984 Oct. 20 (Box 20)
  - Duke/Maryland, 1984 Oct. 27 (Box 20)
  - Duke/Georgia Tech, 1984 Nov. 3 (Box 20)
  - Duke/Athletes in Action, 1984 Nov. 14 (Box 21)
  - Duke/NCSU (football), 1984 Nov. 17 (Box 21)
  - Duke/UNC (football), 1984 Nov. 24 (Box 21)
  - Duke/St. Louis, 1984 Nov. 26 (Box 21)
  - Duke/William & Mary, 1984 Nov. 28 (Box 21)
  - Duke/Appalachian State, 1984 Dec. 5 (Box 21)
  - Duke/Virginia, 1984 Dec. 8 (Box 21)
  - Duke/Davidson, 1984 Dec. 17 (Box 21)
  - Duke/Southwestern, 1984 Dec. 19 (Box 21)
  - Duke/Univ. of Alabama-Birmingham, 1984 Dec. 28 (Box 21)
  - Duke/Southern California, 1984 Dec. 29 (Box 21)
  - Duke/Virginia, 1985 Jan. 5 (Box 21)
  - Duke/Wake Forest, 1985, Nov. 10 (Box 21)
  - Duke/Wake Forest, undated (Box 22)
  - Georgia Tech/Virginia, undated (Box 22)
  - UNC/NC State, undated (Box 22)
  - Virginia/NC State, undated (Box 22)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 22)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 22)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 22)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 22)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 22)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 22)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 22)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 22)
  - Duke/Colorado, reel 2, undated (Box 22)